<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James writes about food</title>
    <link>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James writes about food</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb karahi</title>
      <link>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/log/2019-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/log/2019-01/</guid>
      <description>Adapted from this recipe
Ingredients  1kg lamb kneck, on the bone
 2 onions, roughly chopped
 half a bulb of garlic, peeled
 3 green chillies
 5cm piece of ginger, peeled and roughly chopped
 1 tbsp ground coriander
 1 tsp turmeric
 1 tsp red chilli powder
 1 cinnamon stick
 2 black cardamom
 4 green cardamom
 4 cloves
 200g tomatoes, chopped</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pressure cooker congee</title>
      <link>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/pressure-cooker-congee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 01:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/pressure-cooker-congee/</guid>
      <description>Congee with chives, chilli oil, soy sauce and fermented cabbage
Ingredients  1 cup long grain rice 9 cups water  Equipment  Pressure cooker  Process  Combine rice and water, heat in pressure cooker Once the pressure cooker reaches high pressure, cook for 20 minutes Release the pressure quickly, and take the lid off The congee will look watery. Whisk it till it reaches a consistency you like Season, add toppings (see below)  Variantions I serve congee with a few toppings, usually made up from things I have in the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brine fermented cabbage</title>
      <link>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/brine-fermented-cabbage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 20:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/brine-fermented-cabbage/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 head napa cabbage (Chinese cabbage) salt  Equipment  A plastic or glass container of jar, large enough to fit the cabbage Digital weighing scales  Process  Split the cabbage into quarters. I like to cut half nearest the stem with a knife, then tear the leaf half apart. Place the container on the weighing scales and tare it Put the cabbage in the container, add just enough water to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loaf tin bread</title>
      <link>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/loaf-tin-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jameswritesaboutfood.com/posts/loaf-tin-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  450g strong white flour 50g strong brown flour 10g instant yeast 10g salt 325g water  Equipment  Stand mixer 1kg loaf tin  Process  Combine ingredients in the bowl of a stand mixer Knead until the dough comes together and feels smooth, about 10 mins Add some olive oil to the bowl, and roll the dough in it to stop it drying out or sticking to the bowl Cover bowl with a tea towel and let rise until it&amp;rsquo;s doubled in size, around two hours Pour dough out onto a floured work surface, shape into a log Place log into loaf tin, seam side down Cover with a tea towel and let rise for 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>